walottery.com 2016-11-23

# Washington's Lottery

Thank you for visiting the Washington's Lottery website and reviewing our Privacy Notice. This statement addresses collection, use and security of and access to information that may be obtained through use of Lottery Digital Services, including the website and mobile app. This notice covers the following topics:

  * Information Collected and How it is Used
  * Personal Information and Choice
  * Public Access to Information
  * Regarding Certain (Personal/Private) Information Use
  * Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information
  * Cookies (and Applets)
  * Security
  * Disclaimer
  * Use of Site
  * Limitation of Liability
  * Contact Information

#### Information Collected and How it is Used

If you do nothing during your use of Lottery Digital Services but browse, read pages or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information is fully anonymous does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

  1. The Internet Protocol address and domain name used. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol address to direct Internet traffic to you. This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your service provider (e.g. xcompany.com or yourschool.edu).
  2. The type of device, browser and/or operating system you used.
  3. The date and time you visited this site or app.
  4. The Web pages or services you accessed at this site or app.

The information we automatically collect or store is logged by Cole & Weber and is used by Washington's Lottery to improve the content of our Digital Services and to help us understand how people are using our services. The Lottery analyzes this information to determine how our site and apps are being used, so that we may continually improve their usefulness to the public.

#### What We Collect If You Volunteer Information

If during your visit to our website you participate in a survey, send an email, or perform some other transaction online, the following additional information will be collected:

  1. The email address and contents of the email, for those who communicate with us via email.
  2. Information volunteered in response to a survey.
  3. Information volunteered through an online form for any other purpose.

We use your email to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you may identify, to further improve our website, or to forward the email to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information is used to formulate Lottery player demographics and player preferences.

#### Personal Information And Choice

You may choose whether to provide personal information online. "Personal information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable with that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us email, participating in a survey, or completing an online form. You may choose not to contact us by email, participate in a survey or to provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to use the Lottery’s apps, browse the Washington's Lottery website and read or download any information provided on the site.

If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law. If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact Washington's Lottery Legal Services as shown in the Contact Us section of this web site.

Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by email will be treated the same way as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.

#### Public Access to Information

All records, including electronic, that are in the custody of Washington’s Lottery are subject to the Washington State Public Records Act [RCW 42.56](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=42.56). The Washington’s Lottery complies fully with the Public Records Act.

#### Review Of Certain (Personal/Private) Information Use

Washington's Lottery may request you to provide certain personal information in order to identify player demographics or establish a player information base. The information is requested in order to identify Lottery players' preferences or opinions. You may choose not to provide this information and there are no consequences to doing so.

#### Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information

You can review any personally identifiable information we collect about you by using the information in the Contact Us section in this web site. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting an email with a daytime telephone number where you can be contacted requesting that Washington's Lottery correct the inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. [RCW 43.41A.140](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/dispo.aspx?cite=43.41A.140)

#### Membership Requirements

My Lottery is a voluntary, Web- and app-based feature designed for players. Membership is strictly voluntary and in no way affects consumers' ability to interact with the Lottery, such as purchasing tickets or winning a Lottery game. Membership is dependent upon being a Washington resident age 18 or older with a valid e-mail address and Internet connection. If a member's e-mail address changes, the change should be made to their My Lottery profile in order to retain their membership.

My Lottery membership is open only to persons of the state's legal gambling age, which is 18. Any attempt to circumvent these requirements by entering false data into the sign-up form constitutes fraud on the part of the user. Users accept full responsibility for the profiles they create.

#### My Lottery Email And Push Notification Practices

By joining My Lottery, users acknowledge and accept that Washington’s Lottery may send them e-mails and mobile push notifications that include information we believe they may be interested in as a member. As part of My Lottery membership, users may opt-in various e-mail and push notification subscriptions (including, but not limited to, Winning Numbers/Jackpot Amounts, Lottery News, Promotions and Surveys) to receive regular e-mails and/or mobile push notifications with specific content as described in the My Lottery sign-up form. Washington’s Lottery will be tracking the open rate for these messages to assure good customer service and timely delivery. To discontinue receiving such messages, users may opt-out by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our emails, or by disabling push notifications in the My Lottery section of the Washington's Lottery mobile app. Or click here, log in and unsubscribe. Opting out of these messages will NOT cancel their My Lottery membership.

#### Cookies (and Applets)

The Lottery may place a "cookie", a small text file, on a visitor's hard drive. This cookie contains a randomly generated user ID in order to track unique site visits. The Lottery does not uses cookies to store any personal information. The cookie does not contain personal information and does not compromise your privacy or security. This cookie can only be read by Lottery servers and assists us with the statistical analysis necessary to assure site functionality and responsiveness, help with sign-in; provide targeted ads; to combat fraud; and analyze site operations.

Applets are tools downloaded to your computer to work with the software you have. Applets are intended to enhance your browsing experience by enabling you to view information in a unique manner or enable access to information that your computer would otherwise be unable to access without the applet. We do not use applets.

#### Security

Cole & Weber, as developer of the Washington's Lottery website, and Washington's Lottery, as manager, have taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained by Washington's Lottery. These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, to block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession. This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as foolproof, the security of information provided via Washington's Lottery websites.

#### Disclaimer

The Lottery links only to those websites related to its mission and purpose. The Lottery does not link to any website that exhibits hate, bias, discrimination, specific religious views, political positions or candidate support, or social agendas. The Lottery reserves the right to deny or remove any link that contains misleading information or is determined to be in conflict with the Lottery’s mission or policies. The information posted on Washington's Lottery (Lottery) digital properties and may include hypertext links or pointers to information created and maintained by other public and/or private organizations. The Lottery provides these links and pointers solely for our visitors' information and convenience. When visitors select a link to an external digital site, they are leaving the Lottery site and are subject to the privacy and security policies of the owners or sponsors of the external digital site.

  * The Lottery does not control or guarantee the accuracy, relevance, timeliness or completeness of information contained on a linked website.
  * The Lottery does not endorse the organizations sponsoring linked websites and does not endorse the view expressed or products offered therein.

Neither the State of Washington nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at their own risk.

The Washington’s Lottery makes every effort possible to make sure that winning numbers information posted on its website is accurate and available within 24 hours from when winning numbers are drawn. However, in the event of an error the winning numbers and prize amount information in the official records of the Washington’s Lottery will stand as the final determination.

#### Use Of Site And App

Washington’s Lottery authorizes you to view and download the materials at this website ("Site") and the Washington’s Lottery Mobile App (“App”) only for your personal, non-commercial use, provided that you retain all copyright and other proprietary notices contained in the original materials on any copies of the materials. You may not modify the materials at the Site or App in any way or reproduce or publicly display, perform, or distribute or otherwise use them for any public or commercial purpose. Any use of these materials on any other website or networked computer environment for any purpose is prohibited. The materials at the Site and App are copyrighted and any unauthorized use of any materials at the Site or App may violate copyright, trademark, and other laws. If you breach any of these Terms, your authorization to use the Site or App automatically terminates and you must immediately destroy any downloaded or printed materials.

#### Limitation of Liability

IN NO EVENT WILL WASHINGTON’S LOTTERY, ITS SUPPLIERS, AGENCIES, OR OTHER THIRD PARTIES MENTIONED AT THIS SITE BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER (INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, THOSE RESULTING FROM LOST PROFITS, LOST DATA OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) ARISING OUT OF THE USE, INABILITY TO USE, OR THE RESULTS OF USE OF THIS SITE. IF YOUR USE OF THE MATERIALS, INFORMATION OR SERVICES FROM THIS SITE RESULTS IN THE NEED FOR SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION OF EQUIPMENT OR DATA, YOU ASSUME ALL COSTS THEREOF. APPLICABLE LAW MAY NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, SO THESE LIMITATIONS OR EXCLUSIONS MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.

#### Contact Information

Washington's Lottery  
814 4th Avenue East  
Olympia, WA 98506

Customer Service Line  
(360) 664-4720

TDD Users  
(360) 586-0933

Email
